<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:lang="en" xml:id="zym.message" version="5.0">
    <title>Zym_Message</title>

    <para>
        <classname>Zym_Message</classname> provides an infrastructure to relay messages 
        between objects that don't necessarily know each other.
        This provides a loose coupling between components and makes your app more flexible.
    </para>

    <section xml:id="zym.message.registering">
        <title>Registering a message</title>

        <para>
            Registering to a message is done at <code>Zym_Message</code>:
        </para>

        <example xml:id="zym.message.registering.example">
            <title>Registering a message</title>
            <programlisting role="php"><xi:include href="message/example/registering.php" parse="text" /></programlisting>
        </example>

        <para>
            In this snippet, an object is attached to the testEvent message.
            All posts that are sent to the ‘testEvent’ message will then be passed to
            the <code>$receivingObject</code>. By default the notifications will be posted to the
            <code>notify()</code> method. An optional third parameter in the <code>attach()</code> method allows
            you to use a custom method.
        </para>

        <para>
            In this case, all ‘testEvent’ notifications will be posted to the
            <code>customMethod()</code> method in <code>$theReceivingObject</code>. There is a special attach
            method called <code>attachCatchAll()</code>. An object that is registered to the
            catch-all will receive all notifications. If you want to unregister an
            object from the message dispatcher you can call the <code>detach()</code> method. This
            method takes one mandatory and one optional argument. The first argument is
            the object you want to detach. The second, optional, argument is the
            message that you want to detach the object from. If the second argument
            is left blank, the message dispatcher will remove the object from all
            notifications. Don’t forget to detach an object when it’s destroyed! See the next section for an example
            of how to make sure this gets done.
        </para>

        <example xml:id="zym.message.example.complex">
            <title>Attaching, Detaching and Receiving Notifications</title>
            <programlisting role="php"><xi:include href="message/example/complex.php" parse="text" /></programlisting>
        </example>

        <para>
            In the example above the MyClass instance is automatically registered
            to the ‘testEvent’ message at instantiation. If and when the
            ‘testEvent’ message is sent, the <code>notify()</code> method will receive it so it
            can be processed. Note the <code>__destruct()</code> method which explicitly detaches the
            object from the message dispatcher.
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>
